Hello, learn German in Hindi,
welcome to this episode. In the last episode,
we discussed one exam, less one and
raw one time. Today we will solve it, so let's
start. Right now you will
see on the screen which parts of this question are
very simple. In the
first part, you have to
decide something with your partner, whether
you want to plan a party
or you want to travel, and later we will
see these details. We sleep on 28th March.
After that, we have to give a small presentation on whether
children should be given mobile phones or
not. We have to give a small typing presentation for that. There are
40 marks for that and
your partner examiner will ask questions on the presentation you gave.
Answer them and give him feedback on your partner's presentation.
Ask him questions,
this is the third time. 16 marks for him and
how would you get treated in Pakistan,
Pranav Centers House Prakhar for that and
16 marks for the total, if you see, the total is
60% on Monday, the next day  If you have passed,
before going into the details, if you remember this line,
like you will check on this point,
we will see that the accepted
points are the same, first add new room, have you covered all your
points, have you spoken on all the points, is
this fruit, second is how it is run, but if you
answer in part-1, then you are doing this
support interaction,
friend, you are speaking on your own, are you
listening to that too, are you doing traction,
and in part-2, when you give presentation, then
your thing is that you are taking it slowly and
votes to render 1954, we have seen
how your awards are, there are BRICS and whether you
handle grammar behind or not, that's okay,
so here you will be done
and in these, 16 March is
for your own views,
how do you treat this, okay, so this is
how it happens, we will see, so
basically distance general, this park
means that both you and your partner
give the examination together,
if there is no partner in this Indian year  So you
jump on the World Cycle Examiner ad, okay, so
what happens in this is that you and your partner go
inside, then you are
given questions, you sit separately and then
you are given two topics, that is, two things only,
first, what do you have to plan together
and second, the youth has two-three categories, out of which
you have to choose the one which you find easy
and you have to score points on it,
I will tell you later, how to score those points,
okay, so this 15 minutes time is over, then
both of you go in
front of both the sections, then the
examiner says, brother, I mean sleep
smell from man, how are you, what is your name,
how long have you been learning Shravan, German, quick, tight,
just and there is no way for batting,
but always better to be smiling, a
little happy, it always gives a good impression, okay,
then he says, let's start
planning, then you both are
told to start, the first topic,
so you are seeing on the screen, so
what is there in this, both of you have to
participate in this competition  I had won two tickets
for wearing the sacred thread in my hair and
how will you go there, Baba, for that you have four
points, when will you go, how will you go,
where will you stay, what will you take, these four points are
given, so you have to plan together on this point, it's
very simple, you
can talk to each other and when do they
leave here, do they leave on Saturday, oh, if we
leave on that Chaf Avin, then it will be like this, okay, so
they say by bus or train, and the train has become very
expensive, that's all they want, okay,
and then my grandfather lives there, can
we stay with him, man, it will be very far, is it
better than that, can I stay in a hotel,
and what can we take, it will be cold,
we can take flowers and something else, we
can talk about that now, if you want, you
can also add extra points to each other, or like if
we see something worth seeing there, and
then if there is something very famous there, we can try it,
you can also add another point, it's
very simple, if you want to do normal
planning, then you don't need much for this.  Is there any
need to use a radiometer
or there is nothing, still if it is possible for you then
you can use coffee, you
can say Vivek Roy, if the quantum is
not clear then you can open normal, by
doing your smart, you
can take your solution, whatever he says you can say this
channel totally day etc.
there or if he does not like it then I do
n't know friend it would be good that it is in discussion like this,
this Vansh verbs sir, you can say like this,
I have made it simple, the planning is
important that there should be a dialogue between you both,
if he is not speaking much then he should
speak a little, rather
what is your opinion on this subject or ask him, if he is
speaking too much then I asked him
that should I speak a little in this, can you
ask like this, don't like, share and
Sursagar, should I say something about that,
if he is saying something etc., I could not hear anything
properly then don't worry you can ask him
that will I speak once again, do I feel
confident, turn of animals in them  You
can report that don't worry about life, tell me about it, then don't worry,
this is a very simple
time, it was just an interaction, we were doing jobs in the
second time, you saw that you will
choose the theme, so what happens there,
see, they have not given you any restructuring of any theme, whatever the theme is,
in that guide also we had written human, well here
we have to write the information, but what are your
assessments here, they have given you such
5 points, already any team,
those points were always taken, which is
that team, speak on that, then speak on your own
experience, then
after that, what is the condition of your country,
where you come from,
then give your advantage and disadvantage
and give your opinion accordingly and in the end
say thank you etc. and so no matter which country it is, it will
always remain the same, okay, so
for example, now see, you must be seeing in your skin
what is the team because should children be
given mobile phones or not
What can you say on that? I say in Hindi
that I feel that there is
no need to give mobile phones to children.
When I was young, there were no mobile phones in our time. If you
come to Voice, you will get a mobile phone. My
daughter also uses mobile phones sometimes.
But nowadays in India, people
use it a lot, not only for playing but
also for studies. According to me, there are
many such tips that
children's eyes can get damaged. They
remain on the mobile all day, they do
not play and because of that, they can have health
problems. You can say anything like this that
you did not get money. I know that there are a few
advantages, that is,
you can learn from it. That is a vow that you can understand. You
can put an ad on the road that you have to
say in your affidavit that children should
not be given mobile phones because it is
not good for their health. It is simple. Right again,
how to make it, you can directly say
that they should be stylish,
intelligent and depression in the auditor.
Then, in some places, people have the habit that  Brother,
what are you going to say and say again
sorry to you, waist in the waist, arm and
eye donation and you started I do
n't do it myself, I will start speaking directly
and then you can start putting what
happened in my childhood, there is
no need to fry from the side of these minors,
what happens in heart condition on that side, you
can say from this side if you are positive then
if you can melt it, break them there,
after that, if your
style is very good then subscribe to each other,
like and subscribe, how can you say,
this attack was in subscribe, you can,
because it is superhit, why on the side you
can say that you paid attention, so
I thank you, this clash Ramesh courier of
exam cut is very simple, there is no need to do anything different, what do you
say and your hair
is the words, now the time we have free is connected with it,
Aishwarya, you will give this presentation,
your partner will
ask how it went, how did he like your
presentation and ask another question, you
answer his question properly, then the
examiner will also ask you any question, answer that too
calmly  Answer then when your partner will be there
till his presentation is done
listen to you carefully then tell him that you
spoke very well and I have another question
this difference is you are the fruit of Saunth Mian Gud this
Banwa Nokha in a frog like this you can say but it is
not a big deal so this is
your third one and when both of them are done
then the examiner will say thank you you
gave a very good exam bye guys now we
come to the tips okay so first of all
what can you do before the examination you
can speak as much as possible
my tip is always that by calling German for 5 minutes 15 minutes
every day there are a lot of waits
in the beginning you can talk to yourself right now
I want to drink tea so do this mister testing
some right things and as you go ahead
you can also find a partner a month or two before the examination and
practice with that partner and I have
given some opinions in the description you can
select some opening stock
then it will help you celery if you
see what you have to do you will be absolutely  You have to
plan on the driver of a simple party and
speak on the theme of like in a very simple thing update, if you know how to speak properly then there is
no need to do anything different for the village, whatever disease you had, you must have done it for those who are
already veins, even though it is
metal time, the notification, you must have done
more than this for your white color, so
you don't have to do anything different,
just practice speaking, right now
why the exam, during the exam,
these first 15 minutes are
very important for your preparation, in that
you can understand calmly
and can make points, so I personally
believe that what should I do calmly first of all, first
look at the first point carefully, then
choose calmly which of the other themes you find easy and then
make points on that, generally it is said that in the first one
you have to plan 1 inch, you have to
react to the other, so much is
not in your hands, so make a notice of 56 minutes
and more time is 9-10 minutes  20 The
points you had to make for your presentation,
Agyeya, depends upon you. For me, it is good
if you do not make the notice in complete sentences.
Firstly, time will be wasted and secondly,
you have to return it. If you are reading,
this is not a book to be read. Similarly,
Ajay Devgan Govinda Examiner, then do
not write complete sentences, just write the points that you have to
write, that is, mobile, styler, nice,
elders, one by four, trailer, caller, mind. If
you understood its meaning, then if
you keep this notice properly, it will be easy for you to proceed further.
Then when the exam starts, stay
in a safe place as much as possible, keep smiling.
First of all, you have to plan,
like I said, try to have more and more of
dialogues, that he tells your points. If the
actor does not stick to his point on his point, then let
him also speak. If he is
speaking too much, then politely say one, if he is
speaking less, then tell him
what he wants till 13. Okay, the
important thing is that you have to
cover all those points. I have given 24, will you do extra?
If you do it yourself then it is even
better that you will understand
that it is not important here that the
dialogue should be there, if you did not understand something then
ask again, don't worry, okay, Khajur,
next time what you have to do in that is that
I will give you time, wait, wait, wait, you have to speak for 3 minutes,
so do not forget to be too fast,
speak calmly, if you say yes, then there must be a mistake,
suddenly you got stuck while speaking, you are
not able to understand something, calm down and
start again, it's okay, means
reach the point where you stopped, start speaking again from
there, there is no tension, the
limit of other things is simple, look at it, speak in simple characters, it is much better than
speaking with complex mistakes, it is always no matter that
you do not get time to collect it,
hence it is
important that the other person understands the point, so do
not make very complex sentences, keep it simple, do not try anything new
there in the examination pointer, keep speaking the same way as
your friends do, speak
on all the points, bean very  Make them
speak on all the important points,
if it is important, see that it is not about studying, this is
not an exam for studying, then when you see the notice, then write it
down, now look at it like a winner,
look at your partner and say and give
advantage, I have understood it and the third time it is very
simple, brother, if it is the
presentation of the person in front of you, then say come, you did very well
and then tell him that Baba, I have
one more question and when he asks questions, it is an
exam, when Khushi asks, then answer it, it
is very simple, and if you know how to
speak properly, then you do not need to do anything different for the problem,
stay calm there, this is very good,
I hope that you have also
understood the quarter of one examination properly, we will meet
in the next episode, thank you